Register of the Center for the Study of Popular Culture Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Beverly Prescott Hotel, Los Angeles, 1995. (Folder 94: 14)
  Menu and general information
- Century City Hyatt, Century City, Los Angeles, California, 1996. (Folder 94: 15)
- Century Plaza Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1995. (Folder 94: 16)
- Individual Rights Foundation, 1994. (Folder 94: 17)
- Religion and Prime Time Television conference, sponsored by the Center for the Study of Popular Culture, the American Cinema Foundation (ACF) and the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), 1994 October? (Folder 94: 18)
  Agenda and letter
- Davespon, 1994 October 13. (Folder 94: 19)
  Clippings and letter
- Insider's Report, 1995. (Folder 94: 20)
  Announcement, letters, and related materials
- Newsletter--Center News, 1994. (Folder 94: 21)
  Clippings, notes, printed matter, and miscellany
- Center newsletter--Photos, 1995. (Folder 94: 22)
  Order forms and invoices
- Individual Rights Foundation (IRF)--Clippings, 1994. (Folder 94: 23)
  Includes court papers and year-end report
- New Mexico--Speakers, 1994. (Folder 94: 24)
  Clippings, letter of invitation, and related materials
- 1011 Shattuck--Financial records, 1979-1999. (Box-folder 95: 1)
  Includes 1 compact sound cassette and 1 Individual Rights Foundation pin
- Miscellany, 1989-1996 (Folder 95: 2)
- Joe Lieberman, 1995 August 14. (Folder 95: 3)
  Contract, invoice, list, and policy report
- Task Force, 1995 September 9. (Folder 95: 4)
  Agenda, clippings, invoices, letters, lists of guests and industry representatives, and photography order
- Alan Keyes, Radisson Bel-Air Summit Hotel, 1995 October 3. (Folder 95: 5)
  Contract, letters, and general information (event cancelled)
- George Gilder, 1995 September 14. (Folder 95: 6)
  Banquet contract, general information, lists, and photo order
- Dinesh D'Souza, 1995 October 2. (Folder 95: 7)
  Banquet order, clippings, invitation, lists, and miscellany
- Pat Rooney, 1995 July 6. (Folder 95: 8)
  Catering deposit, event order, list, letter, and note
- Wednesday Morning Club--Events receipts, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 96: 1)
- Restoration Weekend (formerly known as the Dark Ages Weekend and The Weekend)--Letters of invitation, New Jersey, 2000 July 27-30 (Folder 96: 2)
- George W. Bush event, 1998 April 23. (Folder 96: 3)
  Includes announcements, biography, clippings, invoice, letters, lists, notes, and related materials
- Jim Greenwood event, 1998 April 20. (Folder 96: 4)
  Biography, letter of invitation, and miscellany. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Jim Greenwood, undated
- Henry Hyde event, 1998 February 18. (Folder 96: 5-6)
  Clippings, articles about Henry Hyde, financial records, letters of invitations, lists, notes, and miscellany
- Orrin Hatch event, 1998 April 14. (Folder 96: 7)
  Biography, invitation, invoice, lists, and related materials. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Orrin Hatch, undated
- Bob Smith event, 1998 March 8. (Folder 96: 8)
  Invitation, lists, summary of charges, and miscellany
- Billy Tauzin event, 1998 February 19. (Folder 96: 9)
  Includes biography, invoice, lists, letters, note, related materials, and 2 photographic prints depicting Billy Tauzin
- Dee Dee Myers/Arianna Huffington, 1998 May 21. (Folder 96: 10)
  Includes announcement, biographies, clippings, record of expenses, invoice, list of guests, and miscellany
- Jerry Weller event, 1998 May 4. (Folder 96: 11)
  Announcement, biography, invoice, lists, and miscellany
- Dore Gold event, 1998 February 3. (Box-folder 97: 1)
  Announcement, biography, lists of guests, press attendees, and related materials
- George Stephanopoulos speaking event, 1998 March 18. (Folder 97: 2)
  Clipping, letter of invitation to speak, list of attendees, and related materials
- John Stossel speaking event, 1998 November 12. (Folder 97: 3)
  Announcement, invoice, lists of guests, and miscellany
- Bill Frist event, 1998 October 27. (Folder 97: 4)
  Biography, invoice, lists of attendees, and related materials
- Matt Fong speaking event, 1998 October 15. (Folder 97: 5)
  Announcement, biography, invoice, lists of attendees, and miscellany
- Pete Wilson, 1998 October 5. (Folder 97: 6)
  Announcements, invoice, letters of invitation, list, and miscellany
- Matt Drudge, 1998 September 10. (Folder 97: 7)
  Includes announcement, invoice, list of guests, and other related materials
- Newt Gingrich event, 1998 January 15. (Folder 97: 8-9)
  Announcement, clipping, list of invitees and attendees, letters, receipts, seating chart, schedule, and miscellany
- Chris Matthews speaking event, 1999 March 9. (Box-folder 98: 1)
  Biography, invoice, letter of invitation, list of attendees, and related materials
- Leoluca Orlando, 1999 February 19. (Folder 98: 2)
  Biography, invoice, letters of invitation, mailing list of Italian organizations, and related materials
- George Will event, 1999 January 20. (Folder 98: 3)
  Biography, invoice, lists of invitees, and miscellany
- Ben Nighthorse Campbell, 1998 December 7. (Folder 98: 4)
  Announcement, banquet event order, estimate of charges, invoice, and related materials
- Jim Rogan speaking event, 1999 December 3. (Folder 98: 5)
  Biography, list of constituents, receipts, and miscellany. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Jim Rogan, undated
- Lindsey Graham, 1999 November 9. (Folder 98: 6)
  Biography and miscellany (event postponed). Includes 1 photographic print depicting Lindsey Graham, undated
- Walter Isaacson speaking event, 1999 November 3. (Folder 98: 7)
  Announcement, biography, expenses, list of constituents, receipts, and miscellany. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Walter Isaacson, undated
- Tom Ridge, 1999 October 26. (Folder 98: 8)
  Banquet event order, biography, list of constituents, receipt and hotel statement, and other related materials. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Tom Ridge, undated
- Leon Panetta speaking event, 1999 June 9. (Folder 98: 9)
  Announcement, biography, receipts, and miscellany. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Leon Panetta, undated
- John Kasich, 1999 March 31. (Box-folder 99: 1)
  Announcement, biography, invoice, list of invitees, receipts, and miscellany. Includes 1 photographic print depicting John Kasich
- David Drier, 1999 June 1. (Folder 99: 2)
  Announcement, biography, list of guests, and miscellany. Includes 1 photographic print depicting David Drier, undated
- Bill Kristol, 1999 April 7. (Folder 99: 3)
  Announcement, banquet event order, biography, letters, hotel statement, list of invitees, receipts, and related materials. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Bill Kristol, undated
- Harvard Salient, 1997 (Box-folder 100: 1)
  Letter from Kelly Novak to Naomi Schaefer, 1997 February 12, mentions a missing computer disc to be used for David Horowitz's lecture and book signing. Includes an issue of Harvard Salient, 1997 February 24, carrying an advertisement for Radical Son by David Horowitz
- Harvard Forum--Fax cover sheet only, 1997 January 27 (Folder 100: 2)
- Collegiate Network Spring Editors' conference, 1997 March 2. (Folder 100: 3)
  Includes a letter from Stanley Ridgley to David Horowitz, 1997 January 16, and schedule of events
- Richard Nixon Library, 1997 February. (Folder 100: 4)
  Acceptance letter on behalf of David Horowitz from Kelly Novak to Evie Lazzarino, 1996 November 5, for luncheon and book signing
- Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1997 February 28. (Folder 100: 5)
  Confirmation letter, 1997 January 8, from Thomas Henriksen regarding David Horowitz's visit to the Stanford campus
- Pacific Research Institute, 1997 February 27. (Folder 100: 6)
  Announcement, letter, and miscellany
- Washington Institute Policy Studies, Seattle, Washington, 1997 February 25. (Folder 100: 7)
  Agenda, biographical note, thank you letter, and miscellany
- Barnes & Noble, 1997 February 19. (Folder 100: 8)
  Letter to Kimble Jackson. Photo mentioned in the letter is missing
- Olin Center, Chicago, 1997 February 18. (Folder 100: 9)
  Announcement of a lecture to be given by David Horowitz, "Lessons of a Misspent Youth," University of Chicago. Includes advertisement for Radical Son, and miscellany
- New York University School of Law--Lecture, "Radical Son: A Generational Odyssey,", 1997 February 12. (Folder 100: 10)
- Manhattan Institute--Talk on Radical Son, 1997 February 11. (Folder 100: 11)
  Advertisement and remarks about the book, clippings, letter, lists of invitees, and party lists
- Independent Women's Forum--Talk about Radical Son, 1997 February 6. (Folder 100: 12)
- Federalist Society of Sacramento, 1996 November. (Folder 100: 13)
  Announcement, letter of acceptance, menu, and related materials
- Theodore Olson--Speech and book signing by David Horowitz, Washington, D.C., 1997 February 6. (Folder 100: 14)
  Announcement, lists of guests, and Ted Olson's invitee list
- Miscellaneous events, 1997 July – December (Folder 100: 15)
- Annual reports, 1994-1997. (Folder 100: 16)
  Includes Hoover Institution annual report, 1996; Center's Profit and Loss Statements, 1994 January – December; clippings; letter; report on sources of funding; and Hudson Institute annual report, 1996
- Campaign Reform Initiative, 1997. (Folder 100: 17)
  Clippings, press release, and related materials
- Michael Berman, 1999. (Folder 100: 18)
  Information about "campaign style" education, independent expenditure fact sheet, and guidelines for discussion with the lawyer
- Michael Berman--Campaign ideas, 1996 June. (Box-folder 101: 1)
  Articles, clippings, financial records, materials relating to education, race, and revitalizing the conservative party
- Larry Elder--Michael Berman's personal notes, 1997. (Folder 101: 2)
  Includes materials relating to a campaign to reshape the conservative party, clippings, letters, list of media contacts, and miscellany
- Michael Berman--Union campaign file, 1997. (Folder 101: 3)
  Relates to planning an effective campaign concerning the role of unions, various propositions, and the California Teachers' Association (CTA)
- Best Friends Foundation--Information packet, 1999 (Folder 101: 4)
- Larry Elder--800 numbers, 1997 (Folder 101: 5)
- Larry Elder--Mailing, 1997. (Folder 101: 6)
  Clippings and letters relating to the campaign to keep Larry Elder on the air, list of donors, and miscellaneous names
- Larry Elder
  - The Larry Elder Statement--Issues, 1997 January - May. (Folder 101: 7)
  - TV ad package, 1997. (Box-folder 102: 1)
    Letters, list of donors, and miscellany
  - Campaign, 1997. (Folder 102: 2)
    Letters, mailing list, Republican National Committee (RNC) funder list, mailing labels, and miscellany
  - Campaign--Prime list, 1997. (Folder 102: 3)
    Letters and mailing labels
  - Campaign--Jewish, 1997. (Folder 102: 4)
  - Clippings, comments on Hillary Clinton's book, congratulatory letters relating to the success of the Elder campaign, form letters, mailing labels, and miscellany, 1998 (Folder 102: 5)
- A. C. Green Programs for Youth, undated. (Box-folder 103: 1)
  Notes and a card
- Note books, undated
- Court papers--Case against Richard C. Riley, 1993
- Contract between Peter Collier and Regnery Gateway, Inc. for publication of Surviving the PC Campus, 1993 September
- Application by Mark Horowitz regarding a project, "Through the Looking Glass: The Tragic Case of Paul Deman,", 1993
- Diane Blair--Statement about maintaining quality on public airwaves, 1993 September 27
- Interview of Jim Yee by Laurence Jarvik, 1993 September 28.
- Letter proposing joint forum between Center for Communication Policy at University of California, Los Angeles, and American Forum, 1993 November
- Letter requesting David Horowitz to review a book jointly written by Hal Pashler and Jim Johnston, 1993 September
- Some possible titles for a book, undated.
  Includes tentative list of topics and related materials
- Office automation--Proposal, 1993
- "Feminist Witch-Hunt"--Article, undated
- Clippings, 1993
- Speech, Bruce Herschensohn, National Review Institute's conservative summit, 1993 January 23
- Patty Roosevelt interview, 1993 July 9.
  3 compact sound cassettes
- Miscellany, 1993
- 1950s--, 1945-1972. (Box-folder 104: 1)
  Clippings, letters, sketch, and documents relating to the funeral of Dorothy Brown
- Legal documents, undated and 1982-1994. (Folder 104: 2)
  Includes article, clippings, divorce documents, letters, 1 photographic print depicting a mountain range, negatives, 2 35 mm slides, and 37 photographic prints
- 1960s--Parents, 1955-1962. (Folder 104: 3)
  Clippings, financial record of payment to a cemetery, letters, and an issue of Columbia Review
- Closing, 1996-1998. (Folder 104: 4)
  Letter, lists of donor codes and names and organizations, and memorandum
- Oregon trip, 1935. (Folder 104: 5)
- Stimpson, Catherine R. case, 1992-1994. (Folder 104: 6)
  Letters, journals, and report
- School choice--Proposition 174, 1993. (Folder 104: 7)
  Articles, clippings, and miscellany
- Miscellany, 1992-1993. (Folder 104: 8)
  Letters and photocopies of articles Poster, undated
- Interviews of Robert F. Kennedy Jr., Barbara Kirby, Chris and Vicki Lawford, Francis H. McAdoo, Chuck McDermott, Tom Oliphant, Duff Pacifico, Paredes?, Bobby Shriver, Warnecke, and others, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 105: 1-2)
- Department of Defense--Tailhook 91, Part I--Review of the Navy investigations, 1992 September
- Stewardship Journal, 1993 spring
- Online, 1993 July – September
- George Paul Csicsery, 1992-1994.
  Article, clippings, and interview
- Clippings, letters, notes, and printed matter, 1990-1993
- Miscellany, 1996
- Bank of America--Hold notice, 2000 July (Box-folder 106: 1)
- Daily Bruin Online, 2001 April - May (Folder 106: 2)
- Daily Princetonian, 2001 April - June (Folder 106: 3)
- University of North Carolina, 2001 March – May. (Folder 106: 4)
- Fall ad campaign--Campaign for Fairness & Inclusion in Higher Education, 2001 June – 2002 April. (Folder 106: 5)
  Includes advertisements, articles, clippings, letters, and related materials
- Lionel Chetwynd, 1992 March – 2001 June. (Folder 106: 6)
  Includes clippings, letters, record of transactions, and related materials
- Money matters, 2001 July – August. (Folder 106: 7)
  Letter and notes
- Lionel Chetwynd, 1992 December – 2002 September. (Folder 106: 8)
  Includes clippings, letters, and miscellany
- Daily Campus, University of Connecticut, 2001 April - June (Folder 106: 9)
- Lantern, Ohio State University, 2001 April (Folder 106: 10)
- "The Freedom Tour"--David Horowitz's schedule, 2000-2001 (Folder 106: 11)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1997-2003
- Court papers, 2002
- Miscellany, 1998-2000
- Brown University, 2001. (Box-folder 107: 1)
- Colleges--Articles, 2001 (Folder 107: 2-3)
- African-Americans--Issue of reparation, 2001 (Folder 107: 4)
- Duke University, 2001. (Folder 107: 5)
  Question of slavery
- Texas--Slavery, 2001. (Folder 107: 6)
- University of Connecticut and elsewhere, 2001. (Folder 107: 7)
  Controversy over the question of reparation, freedom of speech, and related issues
- Articles, 2001. (Folder 107: 8)
  Relates to controversy created by David Horowitz's advertisement and discussions and protests that followed
- Articles relating to the issues of race discrimination, slavery, and freedom of speech, 2001-2002
- Articles, 1998-2001. (Box-folder 108: 1-9)
  Relate to uproar on college campuses over David Horowitz's views on the issue of slavery, responses, and the effect on David Horowitz's reception at various institutions, 2001
- Reviews of Radical Son, 1997-1999. (Folder 108: 10)
- Radical Son--Coverage, 2001. (Folder 108: 11)
  Articles, remarks, and reviews
- Seven Hills Pictures, LLC, 1998.
  Letter relating to question Of film rights to Radical Son and related information
- Radical Son--Articles, clippings, and letters, 1974-1989
- 11 photographic prints depicting David Horowitz's family, his bride, Huey Newton, and Betty Van Patter, 1974-1989
- Ford: An American Epic--Interviews (Box 109)
  - A-Bugas, 1984-1985 (Folder 109: 1)
  - M-R, 1981-1985 (Folder 109: 2)
  - S-Z, 1984-1986 (Folder 109: 3)
- Articles by David Horowitz and Peter Collier, undated and 1989.
  Includes clippings and letters to the editors
- Interviews. (Box 110)
  Includes notes
  - "The First Senator Kennedy," by Kathleen McCarthy, undated (Folder 110: 1)
  - Molly Hay Dock, Doris O'Donnell, Chalmers Goyart, William Randolph Hearst, Eunice Kennedy Shriver, and others, 1980-1985 (Folder 110: 2-4)
  - William Clay Ford, Martha Ford and others, 1960-1985 (Box-folder 111: 1-2)
- Personal letters, 1977; Blanche Horowitz--Certificates, 1941-1948; flier, 1952; receipt for medical care of Morris Horowitz, 1943; bills for the medical care of Philip Horowitz and his family, 1944; advertisements about Philip Horowitz, undated; and a note to David Horowitz
- Press statement by Bertrand Russell, Rampart memorandum from David Horowitz, and miscellany, undated and 2000
- Correspondence relating to Radical Son and other matters, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 112: 1-2)
- Personal letters, 1963-1966 (Folder 112: 3)
- David Horowitz--Statement, undated (Folder 112: 4)
  regarding financial matter between him and Lionel Chetwynd
- Berman--Republican strategy, undated and 1996-1997. (Folder 112: 5-6)
  Article, clippings, and letters
- Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation--Statement about a book by David Horowitz, 1964 August 5
- Radical Son--Typescript final version, 1995
- Letters, 1960-2002
  relating to David Horowitz's books, family, and court case against Lionel Chetwynd
- "Nuclear Research and Engineering: Progress or Doom?" Article by Ben Horowitz, 1983
- Printed matter, 1969 and 1995
- Organizational chart--Columbia's ruling elite, undated
- Miscellany, undated
- Notes, 1934, and certificates for Blanche Horowitz, 1941-1948; medical bills for Morris Horowitz, Philip Horowitz, and his family, 1944; advertisement about Philip Horowitz, undated; correspondence between Philip Horowitz and Clyde R. Miller, 1934; and examination paper for education course 105E by Philip Horowitz (Box 113)
- Clippings, 1964-1973, and letter, undated
- Photocopies of pictures from newspapers, undated
- Miscellany, 1925-1968.
  Includes class notes and papers, letters, poems, resume of David Horowitz, sketches, and statement
- Correspondence between David Horowitz and others regarding various research and writing projects, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 114: 1-4)
- "The Free World Colossus," by David Horowitz, part III, undated
- Huey Newton--Clippings and articles, including one by David Horowitz and Peter Collier, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 115: 1)
- Articles about Black Panthers, 1974-1993 (Folder 115: 2)
- Correspondence with Tom Hayden, 1986. (Folder 115: 3)
  Includes transcripts of remarks by Tom Hayden at the symposium on Lyndon B. Johnson and Vietnam, Hofstra University, Long Island, New York, 1986
- Writers' Guild of America, West, Inc., 1969-1986. (Folder 115: 4)
  Articles, clippings, and letters
- Elementary School--Mementos, 1948-1955 and; 1994. (Folder 115: 5)
  Includes articles, drawings, and letters, 1948-1955, and a letter from Ruth Horowitz? 1994
- "Some Thoughts on Party Structure," undated, and "Toward a True Education: The Inter-communal Youth Institute,", 1971 August 23. (Folder 115: 6)
  Includes a letter and clipping
- Ruth Horowitz--Letters, 1937-1939 and; 1980
- "The Lear Experience," article and assorted notes, Columbia University, undated
- Clippings and article about Black Panthers, 1978-1994
- An open letter from David Horowitz to Sanford Thatcher and the editorial board, Princeton University Press, 1973; a letter to the New York Times Book Review regarding review of The First Frontier, by Edmund S. Morgan.
  Includes a conversation between two unidentified individuals, 1981?
- Transcript of a telephone conversation with Elaine Brown, undated
- Articles--"Revisionism and the Rectification of a Name," article by David Horowitz? undated, and article by an unidentified author, circa 1960-1961
- Interview with Steven Rockefeller, 1973 October 12
- The Nation, 1980-1983.
  Includes a letter to the editor, "Readers on Horowitz"
- Biographical note on David Horowitz, undated, and his personal letter to Judge Dieden, 1980 September 15
- Letter from Robert Carnegie to David Horowitz, 1994
- Black Panthers (Box-folder 116: 1)
  Includes related materials, 1969-1974
- 1940s--Dad's letter, 1941 (Folder 116: 2)
- Interview of Bill Ayers, 1980? (Folder 116: 3)
- David Horowitz
  - "Left Illusions,", undated (Folder 116: 4)
  - "The Old Cold War and the New,", undated
  - "Better Ron than Red," Voice, 1986 September
  - "Intellectual Life and the Renegade Horowitz," comments about David Horowitz's speech at Berkeley, Voice, 1986 August 26
  - "My Life as a Radical," draft of an article by David Horowitz, undated.
    Includes notes and a poem
  - Interview of Ezra Hendon, undated
  - Congratulatory letter, 1984 August 13
    from Evan Thomas, regarding David Horowitz's book, The Kennedys: An American Drama
- Correspondence, 1962-1966. (Folder 116: 5)
  Includes clippings
- Miscellany, 1967-1985. (Folder 116: 6)
  Letter to William Shulman, 1985 March 23, recommending Ronald Radosh for a distinguished professorship at the Department of History, Queensborough Community College, City University of New York; "A Radical's Disenchantment," The Nation, 1979 December 8; review of "Empire and Revolution," undated; and clippings, 1967-1974
- Review of The Hidden History of the Korean War by I. F. Stone, The World, 1970 January 18, and a letter to the editor, Ballantine Books, Inc., 1960 December 9 (Folder 116: 7)
- SYP Reporter, newsletter, undated. (Folder 116: 8)
  Includes an article, "Harriet Tubman," by Ruth Horowitz
- Ramparts, 1967 May
- Bertrand Russell Center for Social Research--Letters, 1967
- Article by others, undated
- Events, 1970s. (Box-folder 117: 1)
  Brochure, letters, and program
- Miscellany, 1962. (Folder 117: 2)
  Includes David Horowitz's letters to his parents, articles and reviews, bank statement, brochure, clippings, correspondence with others, royalty report, and one photographic print depicting the cover page of Student
- Miscellany--Interview, letters, memo, and transcript of a telephone conversation with Elaine Brown, 1974-1981 (Folder 117: 3)
- Planned Parenthood--Newsletter, 1994 (Folder 117: 4)
- Blanche Horowitz--Employee appraisal and obituary, undated
- Biographical note on Blanche Horowitz and certificate acknowledging David Horowitz as a member of Phi Beta Kappa, Columbia University, 1959 May 6; fragment of a story by David Horowitz, undated; obituary of a family friend written possibly by his mother, undated; and 1 photographic print depicting an unidentified family, 1990 October; and related materials
- Eve Pell--Article, Nation, 1982 March 13. (Folder 117: 5)
  Includes miscellaneous clippings, 1981
- Writings by David Horowitz
  - "The Roots of Alienation: A Critique of the Soviet Draft Program, Root and Branch, undated
  - "The Passion of the Jews," Ramparts, undated
  - "An Empty Doorway," poem, Columbia Review, 1957 summer
  - "Lectures, Learning and Grades: A Dichotomy of Education," The Graduate Journal, University of California, 1962 fall
  - Medicare vs. the Swedish System," American Liberal, 1962 November
  - "Pursuit of Victory" and "Debate and the Cold War," co-authored with Michael Walzer, Views, 1964 autumn
  - "Hiroshima and the Cold War," Liberation, 1965 September
  - "Monopoly Capital," Liberation, 1966 November
  - "Fifty Wars of Cold War," Liberation, 1966 December
  - "Triumph of Arrogance," The Center Magazine, 1974 January - February
- Reviews of Radical Son by Richard Gid Powers and Daniel J. Silver, Wall Street Journal, 1997 February 3, and by Charlton Heston, Los Angeles Times, 1997 March 2